Let's try making a couple of changes to this project.
이 프로젝트에 몇 가지 변경 사항을 적용해 보겠습니다.
Along the way, I'll show you some useful features around Claude Code.
진행하면서 Claude Code 주변의 유용한 기능들을 보여드리겠습니다.
The first thing I'd like to do is move this placeholder text over
가장 먼저 하고 싶은 것은 이 자리 표시자 텍스트를
here on the left-hand side down to the center of this panel.
이 패널의 중앙으로 이동시키는 것입니다.
To help Claude understand exactly what content I want
Claude가 제가 어떤 콘텐츠를
moved, I'm going to take a screenshot of
이동시키고 싶은지 정확하게 이해하도록 돕기 위해,
that area right there, and then I'm going to paste
이 영역을 스크린샷으로 찍어서
it into Claude Code using Ctrl V.
Claude Code에 Ctrl V를 사용하여 붙여넣겠습니다.
Note that it's Control-V and not Command-V
Mac OS에서 익숙한 Command-V가 아니라 Control-V라는 점에 유의하세요. Control-V는
that you might be used to on Mac OS. Control-V is
스크린샷 붙여넣기에 특별히 사용됩니다.
used specifically to paste in a screenshot. I
그런 다음 Claude에게 해당 자리 표시자를 중앙에 배치하도록 요청할 수 있습니다.
can then ask Claude to center that placeholder. After
잠시 검색 후 Claude가 스타일 업데이트를 할 수 있습니다.
a little bit of searching, Claude is able to make the styling update.
그런 다음 브라우저 안으로 돌아가서, 네, 멋지네요.
And then back inside the browser, yeah, looks great. Let
이 앱에서 변경하고 싶은 다음 항목을 보여드리겠습니다.
me show you the next thing I would like to change in this app. I'm going to ask
제목과 설명을 표시하는 카드 구성 요소를 요청하겠습니다.
for a card component that displays a title and some description.
카드는 문제없이 생성되지만, 한 가지 어색한 점이 있습니다.
The card is generated without any issue, but there is one
채팅 인터페이스의 왼쪽에는
awkward thing. On left hand side in the chat interface,
문자열 바꾸기 편집기라는 것이 있습니다.
there's String Replace Editor. That little panel
저 작은 패널은 사용자에게 파일이 생성되고 있음을
right there is meant to indicate to the user that a file is being
나타내기 위한 것입니다. 하지만 지금은 백그라운드에서 사용되는 도구에
created. But right now it's using a very technical term
문자열 바꾸기 편집기라는 매우 기술적인 용어를 사용하고 있습니다.
String Replace Editor for the tool that is being used behind the scenes.
이곳에 사용자에게 좀 더 친근한 텍스트를 표시하고
I would like to show a user a little more friendly text here and
파일이 생성되고 있다는 것과 파일 이름을 사용자에게 알려주고 싶습니다.
just tell the user that a file is being created and the name of
그리고 물론 이 챗봇이 파일을 편집하거나 삭제하는 경우와
the file. And of course, we should also handle cases where
그 외 다른 상황도 처리해야 합니다. Claude의
maybe this chatbot is editing a file or deleting
주의를 끌기 위해, 정확히 무엇에 대해 이야기하고 있는지
a file and other stuff like that. To help guide Claude's
이해하도록 이 스크린샷을 다시 찍겠습니다.
attention, I'm going to once again take a screenshot of this so
그러고 나서 이곳으로 돌아가서 이미지를 붙여넣고 Claude에게
it understands exactly what I'm talking about. Then, back
해당 특정 텍스트를 좀 더
over here, I'm going to paste that image in and ask Claude
사용자 친화적인 메시지로 바꾸라고 요청할 것입니다.
to replace that particular text with some more
이것은 조금 어려운 작업으로, Claude가 이 프로젝트에서
user-friendly message. Now, this is a little
적절한 양의 조사를 수행해야 완료할 수 있습니다.
bit of a tricky task that will require Claude to do
Claude에게 더 어려운 작업을 줄 때마다
a decent amount of research in this project to complete.
Claude의 지능을 쉽게 향상시킬 수 있는 두 가지 방법이 있습니다.
Whenever you give Claude a harder task, there are two
첫 번째 방법은 계획 모드를 활성화하는 것입니다. 계획 모드는
ways that you can easily boost Claude's intelligence. The
Shift-Tab을 두 번 누르거나,
first way is to enable Plan mode. Plan mode
이미 파일 편집을 자동 수락 중이라면 한 번 누르면
is enabled by pressing Shift-Tab twice, or
활성화됩니다.
just once if you are already auto-accepting file edits.
계획 모드에서 Claude는 프로젝트 내용에 대해 훨씬 더 많은 조사를 하고,
In Plan mode, Claude will do much more research
더 많은 파일을 읽고 작업 완료 방법을
over the contents of your project, reading more files
상세한 계획으로 만들 것입니다.
and coming up with a detailed plan on how to complete your
계획을 완료한 후 Claude는
task. After completing the plan, Claude will
작업을 완료하기 위해 무엇을 할 것인지 정확히 알려줄 것입니다.
tell you exactly what it wants to do to complete your task.
그때 이 계획을 수락하면 Claude가 실행하거나,
At that point, you can either accept this plan, and Claude will
Claude를 어떤 식으로든 재지시할 수 있습니다. 예를 들어
implement it, or you can redirect Claude in some
파일을 놓쳤거나
way, maybe it missed some file, or didn't consider
어떤 시나리오를 고려하지 못했을 수 있습니다.
some scenario. The second way in which we can boost
Claude의 지능을 향상시킬 수 있는 두 번째 방법은
Claude's intelligence is by enabling thinking. This
사고 기능을 활성화하는 것입니다.
turns on Claude's extended thinking feature, allowing
이것은 Claude의 확장 사고 기능을 켜서
it to reason more about a particular task. To
특정 작업에 대해 더 많이 추론할 수 있도록 합니다.
enable thinking, there are a handful of different trigger phrases.
사고 기능을 활성화하려면 몇 가지 다른 트리거 구문이 있습니다.
Each one gives Claude a progressively larger token
각 구문은 Claude에게 점진적으로 더 큰 토큰 예산을
budget to think with. Given that this is a trickier task,
제공합니다. 이것이 까다로운 작업이라는 점을 고려하면,
I might ask Claude to ultra-think about the best way to implement
Claude에게 구현 방법을 최적화하도록 요청할 수 있습니다.
it. The last thing to understand is that planning
이해해야 할 마지막 사항은 계획과
and thinking can be used together. So in addition to
사고 기능을 함께 사용할 수 있다는 것입니다. 따라서
this ultra-think, I'm going to also turn on Plan mode
이 최적화 사고에 더해 계획 모드도
as well. And now I'm going to run this and we'll see how well
함께 활성화할 것입니다. 이제 실행하고 Claude가 이 기능을 얼마나 잘 구현할 수 있는지 지켜보겠습니다.
Claude can implement this feature. Now, you might
이제 계획과 사고 중 언제 사용해야 하는지에 대해
be wondering when you should use planning and when you should use
궁금해하실 수도 있습니다.
thinking. Think of these two as handling
이 둘을 가로 폭과 깊이를 처리하는 것으로 생각하십시오.
breadth-first depth. Planning mode is useful
계획 모드는 코드베이스에 대한 광범위한 이해가 필요하고
when you have a task that requires a wide understanding
다양한 영역을 살펴보아야 하는 작업에 유용합니다.
of your codebase and requires looking at different areas.
또한 여러 단계를 거쳐 완료해야 하는 작업에도 유용합니다.
It's also useful when working on a task that requires several
반면에 사고 기능은
steps to complete. Thinking, on either hand, is
특정 까다로운 로직에 집중하거나
useful when you are focusing on a particular tricky
어려운 버그를 해결할 때 유용합니다.
bit of logic or troubleshooting a difficult
두 번째로 궁금해하실 점은
bug. The second question you might have is whether
항상 사고와 계획을 활성화해야 하는지 여부입니다.
you should just enable thinking and planning all the time.
글쎄요, 확실히 할 수 있습니다. 단, 계획과
Well, you certainly can, just keep in mind that planning
사고 기능은 추가 토큰을 소비하므로
and thinking consume additional tokens, so there
사용하는 데 비용이 수반된다는 점을 명심하세요.
is a cost associated with using them. After
몇 분간의 작업 후, 기능이 완료된 것으로 보입니다.
a couple of minutes of work, it looks like the feature is complete. So
따라서 편집기로 돌아가서 테스트해 보겠습니다.
I'm going to go back over to my editor and test this out. So
바로 여기서 이전보다 더 나은 상태 정보를 얻을 수 있습니다.
right away, we can see that we get some better status information here
사용자들은 이제 파일이 생성되고 있다는 것을 알게 됩니다.
than what we have before. Users are now being told that a file
그리고 제가 후속 요청을 보내면,
is being created. And if I send in a followed request,
예를 들어 제목을 변경하라는 요청을 보내면
maybe to change the title. Hopefully
후속 작업에서 해당 파일 편집에 대한
now on the follow-up, we'll see something about editing that file.
무언가를 보기를 바랍니다.
So there we go. So now we're editing the app.jsx file.
자, 여기 있네요. 이제 앱.jsx 파일을 편집하고 있습니다.
Well, I would say Claude definitely succeeded in implementing
음, Claude가 이 기능을 성공적으로 구현했다고 말할 수 있습니다.
this feature. Now that we have made some changes to this
이 프로젝트에 몇 가지 변경 사항을 적용했으므로
project, we should probably commit our changes. Claude
변경 사항을 커밋하는 것이 좋을 것입니다. Claude Code는
Code is a solid Git Assistant. We can ask it to
견고한 Git 도우미입니다.
stage and commit our changes and it will write a
변경 사항을 스테이징하고 커밋하도록 요청할 수 있으며
descriptive commit message for us.
설명적인 커밋 메시지를 작성해 줄 것입니다.